<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on KD&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on KD&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 21:25:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Contact form to Hugo with Google forms</title>
      <link>/posts/add-contact-form-hugo-google-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 21:25:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/add-contact-form-hugo-google-forms/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is great for a static site. No need for complecated setups, no database or data tobe hacked. static sites have ton of advantages but when it comes to dynamic content like contact form it is little bit complecated to setup. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna use Google Forms to setup Contact form on Hugo Static site with custom thank you page on submit.
First open Google form and create a form with Name, Email, Subject and Message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portainer on Wsl2</title>
      <link>/posts/portainer-on-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 19:37:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/portainer-on-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using WSL2 for developping for both personal and Professional use cases. To manage and quick deploy the containers, i’ve been using Portainer. As much as i love to use Terminal, i’m mostly lazy.
I’m assuming you’ve already WSL2 installed and docker is up and running.
First create a volume with following.
$ docker volume create portainer_data Now, install portainer
$ docker run -d -p 8000:8000 -p 9000:9000 --name=portainer --restart=always -v /var/run/docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Git SSH Permissions</title>
      <link>/posts/fix-git-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:59:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/fix-git-ssh/</guid>
      <description>When you try to git push it throws Permission Denied(publickey) error.
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;quot;wp-block-code&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Permission denied (publickey). fatal: Could not read from remote repository. Please make sure you have the correct access rights and the repository exists. When this keeps happening and you think you’ve already added the public key in the GitLab or BitBucket or any other. You might’ve added key in Pageant which comes with putty but git doen’t use the key from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Windows Terminal with single Command</title>
      <link>/posts/launch-windows-terminal-cmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:41:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/launch-windows-terminal-cmd/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft recently launched Windows terminal in the Microsoft Store as the preview. I&amp;rsquo;m already loving it. With continuous updates and it&amp;rsquo;s already my default terminal app. It allows you to run PowerShell, PowerShell Core and even WAL (Windows Subsystem for Linux).
To open Windows Terminal from run Press Win+R and type
&amp;gt; wt </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup No Password Login for Wordpress</title>
      <link>/posts/setup-no-password-login-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:12:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/setup-no-password-login-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Passwords can be tricky. They are hard to remember and easy to guess and easy to be stolen. And there is Human element and our stupid brains always wants use same or similar passwords for login on every other website, including social networks, Personal email and Works emails etc.
When it comes to WordPress, this can be more damaging. If your business website is compromised because of some weak password or any other human elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:05:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog. If you are reading this you&amp;rsquo;ve plenty of time to spare (or waste). So, buckle up. you are going to learn something (or waste tone of time).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>