<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on KD&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on KD&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>KD Puvvadi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 15:13:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Hugo in Windows and Free Hosting with Netlify</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-started-with-hugo-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 15:13:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-started-with-hugo-windows/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide for windows. There are multiple ways to install Hugo in a Windows PC. I prefer Chocolatey. To install, Open PowerShell or Command prompt with elevated privileges. Copy the following and paste in the
choco install hugo To check whether the installation is successful,
hugo version it should output something like this,
&amp;gt; hugo version Hugo Static Site Generator v0.78.1/extended windows/amd64 BuildDate: unknown if you are planning to use Sass for CSS, hugo-extended is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Home Assistant from anywhere securely with DuckDNS, Let&#39;s Encrypt and NGINX</title>
      <link>/posts/set-up-duckdns-home-assistant-letsencrypt-nginx-duckdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 22:09:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/set-up-duckdns-home-assistant-letsencrypt-nginx-duckdns/</guid>
      <description>we&amp;rsquo;ve setup Home Assitant previously. Without static IP, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to access Home Assistant instance out of the home without hassio cloud.But it&amp;rsquo;s a subscription service. One of the reason one might choose Home Assistant is to avoid subscription services from a lot of providers.
DuckDNS Intro Problem without static IP is, ISP&amp;rsquo;s assigns different IP from their pool every time home router restarts or after certain time. assigning DNS to constantly changing IP becomes hassle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Nodemcu to Home Assistant</title>
      <link>/posts/home-assistant-nodemcu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 22:12:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/home-assistant-nodemcu/</guid>
      <description>In the Previous post, we had setup Home Assistant on Raspberry pi. For the first integration, we are going to use ESP8266 aka NodeMCU. Required items as follows
Requirements - ESP8266 - Power Supply - DHT11 Sensor  ESP8266 Setup Our goal today is connecting NodeMCU to HomeAssistant and reading Temperature and humidity data from the DHT11 sensor. To do that we need to install small addon ESPHome from Addon store on Home Assistant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Assistant Setup on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>/posts/home-assistant-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 20:09:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/home-assistant-setup/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m loving Home Assistant. If your home has a lot IOT devices or if you want to get start with Home Automation, Home Assistant is best start. For the beginners, it maybe little intimidating but it is well worth the effort. To get started you need following componenets.
Required Hardware - Raspberry Pi - Power Supply - MicroSD card (Atleast 32GB) - SDCard Reader  Download required Tools First Download Pi Home Assistant Image Here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Contact form to Hugo with Google forms</title>
      <link>/posts/add-contact-form-hugo-google-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 21:25:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/add-contact-form-hugo-google-forms/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is great for a static site. No need for complicated setups, no database or data to be hacked. static sites have ton of advantages but when it comes to dynamic content like contact form it is little bit complicated to setup. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna use Google Forms to setup Contact form on Hugo Static site with custom thank you page on submit.
First open Google form and create a form with Name, Email, Subject and Message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portainer on Wsl2</title>
      <link>/posts/portainer-on-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 19:37:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/portainer-on-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using WSL2 for developing for both personal and Professional use cases. To manage and quick deploy the containers, I’ve been using Portainer. As much as i love to use Terminal, i’m mostly lazy.
I’m assuming you’ve already WSL2 installed and docker is up and running.
First create a volume with following.
$ docker volume create portainer_data Now, install portainer
$ docker run -d -p 8000:8000 -p 9000:9000 --name=portainer --restart=always -v /var/run/docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Git SSH Permissions</title>
      <link>/posts/fix-git-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:59:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/fix-git-ssh/</guid>
      <description>When you try to git push it throws Permission Denied(public key) error.
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;quot;wp-block-code&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Permission denied (publickey). fatal: Could not read from remote repository. Please make sure you have the correct access rights and the repository exists. When this keeps happening and you think you’ve already added the public key in the GitLab or BitBucket or any other. You might’ve added key in Pageant which comes with putty but git doesn’t use the key from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Windows Terminal with single Command</title>
      <link>/posts/launch-windows-terminal-cmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:41:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/launch-windows-terminal-cmd/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft recently launched Windows terminal in the Microsoft Store as the preview. I&amp;rsquo;m already loving it. With continuous updates and it&amp;rsquo;s already my default terminal app. It allows you to run PowerShell, PowerShell Core and even WAL (Windows Subsystem for Linux).
To open Windows Terminal from run Press Win+R and type
&amp;gt; wt </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup No Password Login for WordPress</title>
      <link>/posts/setup-no-password-login-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:12:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/setup-no-password-login-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Passwords can be tricky. They are hard to remember and easy to guess and easy to be stolen. And there is Human element and our stupid brains always wants use same or similar passwords for login on every other website, including social networks, Personal email and Works emails etc.
When it comes to WordPress, this can be more damaging. If your business website is compromised because of some weak password or any other human elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:05:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog. If you are reading this you&amp;rsquo;ve plenty of time to spare (or waste). So, buckle up. you are going to learn something (or waste tone of time).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
